Do you know how many members of Destiny's Child there are?
Uh, well, it depends on what era.
So I'll take that as a yes.
Yes, yes.
Okay.
How many senators are there?
In my state or?
In the United States, how many senators sit in the Senate?
That's a lot of them.
Uh, let's go with 600.
Well, 100, because there's two for each state.
Okay.
And there's 56.
I messed that up.
You know what?
That's pretty cool, though.
Those are honest questions, you know?
That was a clip from the new hilarious political comedy documentary,
An Amanda We Trust.
And in the doc, Amanda Seals heads to the nation's capital, as you can see,
to see what Americans know about their own government and legislation.
She learns, she teaches, laughs a lot, and here she is to tell us all about it.
Welcome back to GMA3.
Thank you so much for being here.
Before we start, that was a fair question, because Destiny's Child had four members at one.
That's correct.
At one time, right?
And then three.
Yes.
Okay.
Do you know who the two is?
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on, Amanda.
No follow-up questions.
No, no.
And we also have to brag about you just for a second.
Your holiday weekend and your trip to Belize.
Can we play the clip here, everybody?
Watch this.
Oh, oh.
I'm sorry.
Are you a collegiate diver?
Did I miss that?
I was a gymnast, but I was also a high school diver.
But you know what?
Let me just say real quick that that moment is really big because I'm afraid of heights,
and I really pushed myself.
So you've got to impress yourself, y'all, especially in your 40s.
I love it.
You've got to do it.
And nail me form.
Thank you.
Very nice.
The documentary, which I watched.
It was hilarious.
Yay!
And I loved it.
But one thing that really stood out to me that was so important was that you were talking
about throwing your cards on the floor.
He's leaving them there.
But you talked a lot about, with your community, about how the government should be part of the
culture.
Yes.
And being engaged in government should be part of the culture.
So I strongly believe that the further that we get away from our understanding of this
system is the more opportunity we give for the system to control us.
Right.
And that is not just for black folks.
I mean, we are seeing a huge labor movement happening in this nation.
We're seeing many people wake up to the realities of that they've been lied to, that they have
been withheld information.
What happened in 2020 when folks hit the streets was that was a real reckoning for a lot of people.
They said, you know, wait a minute.
This isn't okay.
That's why we're seeing books banned, by the way, because it was like, oh, wait, people
are like waking up.
So we need to like try and suppress.
And so what this documentary is, is just like using comedy to try to excite people about
the way they can be the change they wish to see.
Yes.
Absolutely.
How they can be involved.
Yeah.
And this was supposed to be a standup special.
You know, let me tell you.
How do you take a turn to become this big documentary now?
Too much material?
It's flow, not force.
You know, I originally was going to do a standup special and I had the footage.
It wasn't something that I had intentionally went out to shoot, but it was like, oh, I
have this footage.
Let me, let me try and spruce it up with some like segments in DC and I'll make it like I'm
running for office.
Yeah, that'll be fun.
But then when we went to DC, we got so much of an abundance of great footage.
And anybody in production knows that you're usually lucky if you just get what you need,
let alone getting more.
You're like, wait, is this anointed?
And you just, I just said to myself, man, even if we didn't do the standup, we'd have
enough.
Well, careful what you say, because then I realized that the standup footage wasn't as
quality, like technically as the other footage.
And so I had to make a choice.
And that's why I say it's flow, not force, because I had to really listen to my gut, which
said, no, this is the stronger choice.
And then when we actually really looked at the footage with that new lens, we saw this
isn't just a stronger choice.
It's the necessary choice.
We all need to be teaching.
We all need to be sharing and we should all embrace learning.
Yeah.
And so I learned in this process and I got to teach as well.
Just quickly.
You mentioned running for office.
There's just any aspirations, anything that you'd like to announce right here on GMA3.
I would like to announce that I would never run for office.
You know what it is, though?
I really am.
I'm not a reformist.
I really do believe that things cannot be changed solely from the inside.
It's going to require both inside and outside.
The Berlin Wall was not broken down on one side.
It was both sides chipping away at it that took it down.
And so I'm somebody, though, who feels like what I can do on the outside can help bolster
the folks, the progressives, the progressives who are on the inside.
On the inside.
I think right now we're very caught up in the Democrat, Republican.
That's a diversion.
People are showing you who they are.
Believe them.
But in order to do that, you've got to listen and you've got to learn.
I'm so thankful that y'all have me on here to talk about this because, you know, we're in a strike
and there's content that's going to be coming out that's just thrown together.
This is something I've done independently from my own pocket, from my own mind.
And I was able to do it because I didn't have a studio telling me what to do.
I was able to do it this way and this honest because I was able to work with my director,
James Bland, and really just decide how do we make this as most for the people as possible.
So I hope that you all will go to InAmandaWeTrust and we'll seal the deal.
And on that note, we say thank you very much. We appreciate it.
And the best of luck to you, too.
Thank you.
And InAmandaWeTrust is available on the platform in InAmandaWeTrust.com.